Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Marcus Cunliffe papers
1960-1990
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cunliffe, Marcus
MS0125.UA
53 Linear Feet
Contains diaries, correspondence, research notes, articles, chapters from books, syllabi, exam questions, news clippings, correspondence, original military ballads, illustrations, and photographs range in date from 1936-1990 (bulk 1960-1990) documenting Cunliffe's career as a scholar of American history.
Acquisition Information
The papers were donated to the Gelman Library University Archives in 1990 by Cunliffe's widow, Dr. Phyllis Palmer.
Biographical Note
Marcus Falkner Cunliffe (5 July 1922-2 September 1990) was born in Lancashire, England and spent his life studying the history of the United States. Professor Cunliffe was a distinguished historian and expert on George Washington. His seminal book "George Washington: Man and Monument," was first published in 1958. Professor Cunliffe served on the faculty of The George Washington University as University Professor from 1980 to his death in 1990.
As a young man growing up in England, Cunliffe was introduced to America through such writers as James Thurber, Stephen Crane, Ezra Pound, and e.e. cummings. He listened to the voice of Franklin D. Roosevelt and watched American films featuring Greta Garbo, Jean Harlow, and Joan Crawford. Professor Cunliffe read history at Oriel College, Oxford, and earned an M.A. and a B.Litt. from Oxford University. After serving in the British Army during World War II, he was a Commonwealth Fellow at Yale University from 1947-1949. With the opportunity to live in the United States, Cunliffe went there after the war, as he put it, in "complacent ignorance." When he left two years later, he carried with him a wealth of experiences of American culture gleaned from his travels throughout the country.
Upon his return to England, Cunliffe embarked on an impressive academic career. From 1949 to 1964, he was successively Lecturer, Senior Lecturer, and Professor at the University of Manchester, teaching in the areas of American history and institutions. From 1965 to 1980, he was Professor of American Studies at the University of Sussex (which established the Cunliffe Centre in 1991). In 1980 he moved to the U.S. to accept an appointment as University Professor at George Washington University, a rank created by the GW Board of Trustees to attract scholars of distinguished reputation who have made significant contributions beyond a single discipline.
Over the years, Professor Cunliffe held visiting professorships at Harvard University (1959-60), City University of New York (1970), the University of Michigan (1973), and the University of California-Berkeley (1976). In 1978, he was Lamar Lecturer at Mercer University in Georgia. During his career Cunliffe lectured extensively in the U.S., Canada, and Europe, as well as Japan, India, Nepal, Lebanon, Turkey, and Kenya, et al. His fellowships included periods at the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars (1977-78) and at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences in Stanford, California (1959-60). The author or editor of more than 15 books on history and literature, his seminal work was "George Washington: Man and Monument," published in 1958. Other books included "The Literature of the United States"; "The Nation Takes Shape, 1789-1837"; "Soldiers and Soldiers: The Martial Spirit in America, 1775-1865"; and "Chattel Slavery and Wage Slavery: The Anglo-American Context, 1830-1860."
Cunliffe also contributed numerous articles and reviews published in periodicals such as American Historical Review, American Quarterly, Commentary, Encounter, History Today, Journal of American Studies, Manchester Guardian, New Republic, New York Times Book Review, London Times Literary Supplement, and the Washington Post.
Marcus Cunliffe was remembered by a friend as a historian who enjoyed comparing how Europeans viewed Americans and how Americans viewed Europeans. Cunliffe examined the ways societies construct values for themselves and images of themselves, and was a scholar of the first order, who, in "everything he wrote was guided by a code of grace and readability that was a deep expression of his engaging personality."
Marcus Cunliffe died of leukemia in Washington, D.C., September 2, 1990.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
The Marcus Cunliffe Papers consists of 103 boxes, or 53.0 linear feet of materials. It consists of twelve series, and contains diaries, correspondence, research notes, articles, chapters from books, syllabi, exam questions, news clippings, correspondence, original military ballads, illustrations, and photographs. These materials range in date from 1936-90 (bulk 1960-90).
The collection is strong in documenting Cunliffe's career as a scholar. His diaries are of the greatest value, and especially insightful in revealing Cunliffe's observations of English and U.S. history and culture in his lifetime. Another strength of the collection are research notes and correspondence which chronicle the work he did on a number of book projects.
Collection Organization
Organized in twelve series: Diaries and Personal Papers, Correspondence, Conferences, Lectures, Seminars, Symposia, Professional Writing and Consulting Work, Cunliffe's Book Projects: Notes, Correspondence, Contracts, Research Notes/Articles, University Teaching Career, Pamphlets papers, and Reprints, Illustrations and Photographs, Oversize Materials, Books Written and Edited by Marcus Cunliffe, Miscellaneous Materials
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
American civilization; Lantern slides; United States; Diaries; United States -- History; Sussex (England); Washington (D.C.); Great Britain; Photographs; University of Sussex; Cunliffe, Marcus; George Washington University
- Diaries and personal papers, 1936-1990; MS0125 Series 1; 4 Linear feet (Box 8)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of 49 diaries which Cunliffe kept from 1936 until days before his death in 1990. The diaries capture observations Cunliffe made on various subjects. For the period 1936-1950, topics include: the deaths of King George V and Rudyard Kipling, the rise of Hitler and World War II, Cunliffe's years studying at Oxford, war experiences, and his travels throughout the U.S. while a fellow at Yale. For the period 1950-1970, topics include: his development as a historian, the writing of his books George Washington and The Literature of the United States, reflections on the McCarthy era, the Kennedy assassination, and U.S. presidential elections. For the period 1970-1990, topics include observations on Watergate, the Ford-Carter presidential debate, Cunliffe's lectures in Africa, numerous conferences, life in Washington, D.C., and his battle with leukemia.
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 01/01/1936-09/12/1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, VOL 1:, 01/08/1940-03/29/1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, Books Read Theories, Scribbling, 10/1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 03/1941 -- 12/1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (and "Intelligence Notes"), 01/08/1942-08/06/1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, begun at Lesmahagow, Lanarkshire / Ended at Bury St. Edmonds Suffolk, 08/1943-05/1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, VOL 5, VOL 6, 10/01/1944-11/13/1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, VOL 7:, 11/14/1945-02/27/1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, VOL 8: (Oxford) (Bath place), 02/28/1946-06/11/1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 06/17/1946-01/01/1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 01/22/1947-09/09/1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 06/22/1948-08/11/1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 08/12/1948-08/17/1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 08/23/1948-02/13/1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 02/14/1949-08/01/1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 09/23/1950-03/14/1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 05/25/1957-02/14/1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (Manchester) (Cambridge MA), 03/07/1959-12/15/1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 03/1959-12/14/1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 12/27/1959-06/24/1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 07/18/1960-12/20/1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 12/23/1960-05/12/1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 12/22/1962-09/27/1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 10/04/1964-12/31/1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 02/20/1968-06/27/1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 02/20/1968-06/27/1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 08/07/1969-03/24/1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 04/08/1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 09/07/1973-04/15/1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 08/06/1975-09/02/1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 09/12/1976-09/25/1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 08/07/1977-08/31/1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (Washington DC), 09/29/1977-04/06/1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, Datebook/Addressbook, 01/1978-12/1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (Washington DC), 12/10/1980-12/10/1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (Edinburgh), 05/22/1983-05/27/1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (London), 03/31/1986-12/19/1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary, 03/1979-10/1980; 03/1988-05/1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's Diary (Washington DC), 06/06/1989-08/26/1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, "The Other Side", undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, "Personal Account of a Buffalo Operation", undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, "A Squadron", undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, Notebook, 07/1944 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, "Cobots, Kabotschniks -- 1949", undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, Various essays and notes from university, 1940-1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, "War Years", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's Diary and Miscellaneous Notes, Miscellaneous Notepad, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: Certificates relating to Cunliffe's education and application to join British army, 1938-1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers: Cunliffe immigration -- secondary papers, 1961-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Personal Papers: Cunliffe immigration, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers: Cunliffe's appointment calendar, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers: Cunliffe's memorial service, 10/14/1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers: Drawings by Jason Cunliffe, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers: Notes for a novel Cunliffe was working on, 1954-1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers: Notes for a novel Cunliffe was working on, 1961-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers: Notes on content of Cunliffe's personal files and other miscellaneous material, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers: Paper - "Marcus Cunliffe: Historian" by Elizabeth Coffey, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers: Photos - Marcus Cunliffe, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers: Photos and negatives from Cunliffe's books and articles, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers: Photo panel of Cunliffe family- "Advancing or Backing into 1969" (Sharon, Mitzi, Marcus, Antonia, and Jason) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Personal Papers: Photograph - unidentified group, 1950 ca. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1950-1990; MS0125 Series 2; 2.5 Linear feet (Box 13, Box 12, Box 11, Box 10, Box 9)
  This series consists of professional correspondence with people such as C. Vann Woodward, Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., Richard Hofstadter, Adlai Stevenson, C. Wright Mills, Henry Steele Commager, Merle Curti, Lewis Mumford, Carl Degler, and Cushing Strout. There are also letters to and from university presses.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - American Studies International, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Daughters of the American Revolution, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Fishwick, Marshall, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- French, Roderick, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- General, U.K. and Europe, 1977-1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence -- General, U.K. and Europe, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Henrikson, Alan K., 1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - New England College, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Ripley, Wendy, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Society for Historians of the Early American Republic, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Sphere Books Limited and other, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Temple University Press, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- University of Palermo, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Van Doren, John, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Vanni, Francesca Orestano, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Welland, Dennis (including American Studies program history at University Of Manchester), 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- White, George (keeper of Matthiessen room, Harvard University), 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and article "The Voyage to the Colony of Linconia" by Gabor Boritt, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and memos - general, 1975-1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Cunliffe's U.S. immigration, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence to answer, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Arthur Schlesinger, 1973-1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Daniel Snowman of the BBC concerning broadcasts, 1971-1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Enrique Diez, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Krijn ter Braak, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Michel Granger regarding Maurice Gonnaud "Festschrift,", 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Italian-American Conference, Florence, Italy, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Rutgers University Press regarding Cunliffe's review of Cushing Strout's book Visions and Revisions, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with the Folio Society (U.K), 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and articles, 1963-1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Conferences, lectures, seminars, symposia, 1957-1989; MS0125 Series 3; 2 Linear feet (Box 14, Box 13, Box 17, Box 16, Box 15)
  This series features materials ranging from 1957-1989 with the bulk of the material ranging from 1970-89. The material deals with conferences and seminars Cunliffe attended. It contains papers he delivered in Italy, Scotland, Hungary, etc., and lectures delivered to the American Historical Association, Smithsonian Institution, and various colleges in the U.S. and Europe.
  - Conferences, lectures, seminars, symposia, undated (Box 13)
  - Conferences: American Studies Association meeting -- session notes and papers, Miami Beach, 10/1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Conferences: British Association of American Studies (BAAS) conference, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Conferences: British Association of American Studies (BAAS) -- UEA Conference, 04/10/1970-04/13/1970 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Conferences: British Association for American Studies conference - Cunliffe paper and notes, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Conferences: British Association for American Studies conference (reversals on pendulum theories), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Conferences: Caesar, Cromwell, Founding Fathers from AHA conference, 12/1987 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe paper - "North and South, West and East: The Polarizing of American Values," delivered at Italian-American Historical Conference, Florence, Italy, 10/25/1983-10/27/1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper on "North, South, East and West: Polarizing of American Values" - Italian American Conference, Florence, Italy, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper on "North, South, East and West: Polarizing of American Values" - Italian American Conference, Florence, Italy, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper on "North, South, East and West: Polarizing of American Values" - Italian American Conference, Florence, Italy, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper "The Cultural Patrimony of the New United States," Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars conference, 01/26/1984-01/27/1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper "The Widening and Weakening of Republicanism in Nineteenth-Century America" for AHA Conference, Washington, DC, 12/982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Conferences: Cunliffe's paper delivered to American Character and Formation of U.S. Foreign Policy conference, Washington, DC, 02/18/1985-02/21/1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Conferences: European Association for American Studies conference, Florence, Italy, Apr. 12-13, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Conferences: Finletter Fund Conference, New York, NY, 10/31/1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Conferences: Great Lakes American Studies Association conference, Kent State, Ohio, 10/12/1984-10/13/1984 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Conferences: Italian-American Historical Conference, Florence, Italy, 10/25/1983-10/27/1983 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Conferences: Papers from conference on "Atlantic Society:1600-1800," Edinburgh, Scotland, 06/29/1973-07/01/1973 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Conferences: Papers from the European Association for American Studies conference, Budapest, Hungary, 03/25/1986-03/26/1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Conferences: Society for Historians of the Early American Republic (SHEAR) conference, Knoxville, TN, 07/24/1986-07/26/1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Conferences: Society for Historians of the Early American Republic conference, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lectures and Speeches: American Historical Association speech on "Middle Class Democracy in Early Republican America,", 1957 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Bicentennial lecture on the American Revolution, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe lecture - "Education in the American Scheme of Things," delivered at St. Johns College, Annapolis, MD, 09/22/1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's African lecture and notes, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's Jefferson lectures at the University of California-Berkley, 04/1976 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture - "George Washington: Real and Symbolic Hero" for Valley Forge Historical Society, 02/22/1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture - "George Washington: Real and Symbolic Hero" for Valley Forge Historical Society, 02/22/1984 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture - "The Will All Speak English: Some Cultural Consequences of Independence" for U.S. Capital Historical Society conference, 03/1983 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture "The Right of Property: A Theme in American History" University of Leicester, 05/04/1973 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture "Uses and Dangers of the Past" to Virgilian Society, Washington, DC, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture on Lincoln at Gettysburg College (Photo), 11/19/1987 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's lecture at Gettysburg College - "The Doubled Images of Lincoln and Washington,", 1988 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Cunliffe's visit to Canada, 09/1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Doubleday lecture by Cunliffe on Washington as an American Leader, 03/1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lamar lectures - Mercer University, 04/04/1978 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lamar lectures - Chattel and wage slavery, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lecture on approaches to American Studies, Norway, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lecture to Northern Virginia Community College on Parson Weems - notes, 10/14/1983 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lectures at Aarhus University, Denmark, 10/1976 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Lectures in Italy under auspices of U.S. Information Agency, 12/1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Pettyjohn lecture at Washington State University, Pullman, WA, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Rome lectures, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Smithsonian talk - impressions of America, 07/1978 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Lectures and Speeches: Speech and information from the inaugural dinner for George Washington Fellows, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Symposia, Etc.: American Studies Seminar, Helsinki, Finland, 06/08/1977-06/09/1977 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Arizona Law Review - symposium devoted to Robert Nozick's Anarchy, State, and Utopia, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Colloquium on Intellectual History -- City College of New York, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Cunliffe's Department of State seminar "American National Character,", 09/30/1981 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Cunliffe's paper "Congressional Leadership in the American Revolution," Library of Congress Symposium, 05/09/1974-05/10/1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Cunliffe's paper "Problems and Tendencies in American Studies,", 05/1986 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Cunliffe's paper "The Lottery Principle and the United States" Woodrow Wilson Center for International Scholars, Washington, DC, 09/13/1978 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Cunliffe's paper "Virtue and Vainglory: George Washington and His Time" - University of Virginia symposium, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Fraunces Tavern (New York City) George Washington symposium, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Harvard seminar: Federalism/Republicanism, Fall, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Humanities and Public Policy Colloquium, Washington, DC, 05/02/1983-05/03/1983 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Symposia, Etc.: L'Enfant Plan forum, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 8)